Futon, clothes, shoes, toothbrush?
What else?
Huh?!
Rin! Don't disappear on me all of a sudden!
You startled me!
Okay.
Daikichi, get a green one.
Come on! Let's go.
It's dangerous if we don't hold hands.
For me?
ashita no koto wa wakannai
We don't know what'll happen tomorrow.
kore tte gisei to wa chigau
This feels different from a sacrifice.
nanika ga chigau
Something feels different.
batsu ge-mu ja nante omowanai
I'm not thinking of it as a punishment game.
de nande na no ka wa wakannai
I still don't know why.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
Even though I don't quite feel satisfied with that,
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
there's no question that you're important to me now.
owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
There's nothing in this world that's endless.
naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
Isn't it painful having to cry?
ai no Sweet Drops, Sweet Drops
Love's sweet drops, sweet drops.
zutto yume mite itai ne
Don't you want to keep dreaming forever?
motto yasashiku shitai ne
Don't you want to be kinder?
kimi to iraretara Happy
As long as I'm with you, I'm happy.
onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
Don't you think girls can be strong?
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
Even though we can be weak sometimes.
bokura no negai wa Happy Happy Happy
Our wish is for happy, happy, happy.
sonna hibi mo Happy
Those days can also be happy.
Just wanna make you happy
Just wanna make you happy.
I want blue!
Were there always this many parents with their kids here?
I want that!
This?
Yeah.
Umm... Okay. Sure, why not?
About what size are you?
I dunno.
Rin, turn around.
Like this?
What am I supposed to match it to?
I dunno!
Don't flap your arms!
What else do you wear?
Pajamas! Underwear! Shirts! Socks!
You don't need a skirt?
All you've got are pants.
Skirts aren't allowed at nursery school.
I see...
Nursery school?!
It slipped my mind!
Tomorrow's Monday!
Daikichi, I'm tired!
We're almost there, so don't give up.
Okay...
I'm hungry...
We'll be home in a minute, so...
Okay...
You useless bum!
You always bring me crap I don't need!
I'm gonna lose my temper!
You bastard!
Hey!
Don't touch me!
Let go of me!
Uh, excuse me...
Yes, this is the Maeda residence.
Oh, please accept my condolences
over your sudden loss.
Yes, please wait a moment...
Haruko-san, it's Daikichi-san.
Uh, okay. Thank you!
Oh, Haruko?
Sorry, I didn't know your cell number.
It's okay.
Tell me, how do you register
for nursery school?
Nursery school...
You really did take Rin-chan home?!
Are you sure about this?
For now...
What do you mean, "for now"?
So, anyway, I can't
take off work tomorrow.
What kind of procedures need to be followed?
Look, you can't just get accepted instantly.
Can you do something on your end?
What can I do?
For starters, I'd consult with the city office...
It's Sunday night.
What?
Nothing, it's over here.
Mama, is that Rin-chan?
Is everything okay?
Rin-chan!
Reina, please!
This is important!
Rin-chan!
There's an emergency temporary nursery school...
Emergency temporary nursery school...
Rin-chan!
What? Dai-chan?
Rin-chan! Rin-chan! Rin-chan! Rin-chan!
Nothing, it's over here.
I'm almost done, so wait!
I hate waiting!
Haruko-san, I'm going to turn off the miso soup.
Okay! Thank you.
Hey... It sounds like you're busy, so I'll call back later...
Rin-chan!
Emergency Temporary Nursery School
Man, there are hardly any of them...
So, my commute time is suddenly doubled...?
Yeah. Yeah. I'm good.
This one's pretty close, but I can't get out of the office by six...
Let's play again.
Yeah. Bye-bye, Reina-chan. Talk to you later!
This looks like a good one,
but they accept kids on an emergency basis for only 10 days...
Bath...
Just wait a little longer...
Daikichi! Daikichi!
It's morning...
Yeah... Sorry...
Did you sleep here?
The futon is weirdly warm.
Take this off!
Yeah, yeah.
About the nursery school we're going to today...
Thank you for the food!
Thank you for the food.
You're not supposed to eat with your elbow on the table!
There. Sorry.
Listen, the nursery school you're going to today is only temporary.
Temporary?
Only until we find a place that will officially let you attend.
What's "officially"?
It means like, "for real"...
Or, not quite...
Never mind my hair!
Are you okay?
I'm fine...
F-Fine...
I see it!
Put me down! Put me down!
What? What?
Would you be embarrassed if other kids saw me carry you or something?
Daikichi...
Yeah...
Well, please take good care of her.
Sure. We'll see you later.
Don't look at me like that!
I won't be able to make it back while it's still light out,
but I'll come as fast as I can.
I promise.
Pinky swear.
If I lie, I swear
I'll swallow 1000 needles...
Damn it!
My finger was cut off!
That's not how the song goes!
Well, see ya! Wait for me here, Rin.
I'm sorry, Rin.
I didn't take your feelings into consideration.
You had nothing to do with your mother's circumstances or Grandpa's lifespan,
and yet you were left behind with the lonely reality.
Did you think I was going
to leave you behind too?
I'm sorry.
I'll never let that happen to you again...
Read it to me.
Sure!
Kawachi-san. Wanna get some lunch?
I brought this.
I need to leave a little early today...
Oh, yeah? Then I'll see you in a bit.
Working really hard from the beginning of the month, huh?
That's not it.
Take a photo of this sample.
Okay.
Kawachi-san! You've got a call from outside line #4 about the private viewing.
Coming.
Hello, this is Kawachi.
Bye-bye!
Let's keep going!
Yeah.
Kawachi...
Yes! Excuse me...
You're late!
Sorry about that. Go and put your regular clothes on.
All right!
Rin-chan, don't break it, okay?
Yeah...
Bye-bye!
Bye-bye...
Yes, please wait one moment.
Kawachi-san.
It's Miyata-san from Mitsutomo Trading.
Hand it over...
Hello, this is Kawachi.
Thank you for your patronage.
Hello, Kawachi here.
Yes...
I'm terribly sorry.
Yes. I'll be able to leave my company in a few more minutes, so...
I'm sorry.
This nursery school is so far!
Rin! Sorry I'm late!
Welcome back!
I'm really... sorry.
Rin...
Are those potatoes?
They look delicious.
It's burdock!
Daikichi
I swallowed
1000 needles!
Please take care of this.
Kawachi-san! I need your signature!
Not like I need to worry,
but what'll happen if I get a girlfriend?
Daikichi! Daikichi!
Wake up!
Okay... Sorry...
Kawachi, this is what you sent out yesterday, isn't it?
I'm so sorry...
It's unusual for you...
Sorry...
I already apologized to the recipient, so...
Sorry. I'll call them.
We haven't gone out drinking in a while. What do you say?
Sorry, tonight's no good.
Then, how about tomorrow?
I've got something tomorrow, too...
Oh, I get it! Good for you, you sly dog.
Here.
I'm fine!
Daikichi!
Hold on tight!
Daikichi! Run away from the moon!
There's no end!
How long can I keep up this lifestyle?
Mother-Child Health Record Book
These are Rin-chan's.
This is all she has,
but her Maternal and Child Health Handbook and important documents are in here.
Even if it's only for a short period of time,
raising a child is a very difficult thing.
It's Rin who has it the most difficult...
Sorry. I'm just gonna take a peek...
She's got the same mouth...
All the relatives are talking about you like you're some foul villain.
But I wonder what the truth is...
Masako-san.
nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
It's a sunny Sunday, early in the afternoon.
kyou wa doko e yukou?
Where should we go today?
kayoi nareta itsumo no michi ga
This path I've grown so used to taking
mabushiku kagayaite mieru
seems to be shining brightly,
terasu atatakai taiyou to
as long as the warm sun is shining
tonari ni kimi ga ireba
and you are here beside me.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
hashagidasu kimochi ni
I feel like frolicking about.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe wa dokomademo
Our voices can go anywhere.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
maiagaru kaze ni nori
I'm riding on the rising wind.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe mo tobihaneru
Even our voices will be bouncing.
What's wrong?
Feel bad somewhere?
In fact, you're sleeping over there now...
M-Me?! Me?!
It's sweat!
Sure, sure... It's sweat, sweat...
Help me take the sheet off.
I said it's sweat!
I'm saying it's sweat too, aren't I?!
Good morning, Rin here.
Yuki-chan is going to English school.
Wake up! Daikichi, you are late.
But Daikichi looks tired.
On the train ride back home, he's always snoring like an engine.
I wonder if it's hard at work.
The next story is "Daikichi's Decision."
Episode 3
Daikichi's Decision
Don't miss it!